SOFTWARE ENGINEER · MATHEMATICIAN

852 Centerwood Drive, Charleston, SC 29412

□ (631) 291-3866 | sam.chong.tay@gmail.com | samtay.github.io | samtay | samtay

Summary _

Skillful problem solver with a background in pure mathematics. 2+ years experience in web development, backend/infrastructure, and devops. Proven ability to quickly ramp up on new languages/technologies. Efficiency nerd who loves Vim, Linux, and xmonad, and enjoys customizing the development environment. Interested in learning new technologies and tools to solve complex, challenging problems.

Experience_

Software Developer Apr 2017 - Present

EXPANDSHARE

Charleston, SC

- Build microservices for core LMS application in Python
- · Leverage tools and libraries such as AWS, S3, RabbitMQ, and AngularJS

Applications Engineer May 2014 - Feb 2017

BLUE ACORN

Charleston, SC

- Streamlined deployment pipeline across the organization.
- · Pushed the most contributions to internal modules.
- Improved developer experience via Tampermonkey scripts and zsh plugins.
- Achieved the most "Play of the Sprint" awards in 2015.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Promoted from Apprentice to Senior within two years for exemplary work quality and productivity.}$

Research Assistant Summer 2011

ASTROPARTICULE ET COSMOLOGIE

Paris France

• Conducted research and data analysis in correlation of temperature variation and phase noise for LOT (LISA On Table), an optical simulator for the LISA mission, under Dr. Hubert Halloin.

Research Assistant Summer 2010

VALPARAISO UNIVERSITY

Valparaiso, IN

• Explored pattern avoidance in ternary trees (combinatorial mathematics) in a team of three undergraduate students under mentor Dr. Lara Pudwell

Skills

- Agile experience in both scrum and kanban, along with Jira, Workfront, and ZenHub.
- Development
- Experience leading an agile team and mentoring junior developers.
- Very efficient workflow from requirements gathering to development execution.
- Experience with direct client interactions and discussing complex technological details with nontechnical stakeholders.

Languages

- Fluent in Haskell, Python, PHP, Javascript.
- Experience with Bash, C, C++.

Software

- · Mastery of Magento.
- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Experience with technologies such as Docker, Ansible, NodeJS, Symfony, MySQL, Rabbit MQ.}\\$

Workflow

- · Proficient in Linux and MacOS.
- Enjoy maximizing productivity with development tools such as git, vim, tmux, xmonad, zsh, ngrok.

Education

Kenyon College

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS AND SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING

Gambier, OH

Sep 2009 - May 2013

Awarded Distinction on Senior Thesis

Awarded Distinction on Si
 Achieved GPA of 3.91

Publications

Pattern Avoidance in Ternary Trees

NATHAN GABRIEL, KATHERINE PESKE, LARA PUDWELL, AND SAMUEL TAY

Journal of Integer Sequences

Dec 2011

http://arxiv.org/abs/1110.2225